<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vaibhav's Blogs</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Vaibhav's Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CSES Graph Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/graph_cses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/graph_cses/</guid><description>List Of Questions: Counting Rooms Counting Rooms Solution Since we're looking for the shortest path from start to end, it's a good idea to use Breadth-first Search (BFS). Start at the position A, and expand in all possible directions (up, down, left, right), but only if the destination cell is accessible (not a wall) and unvisited. While doing BFS, maintain a parent map to keep track of the cell from where we reached the current cell.</description></item><item><title>Top 50 Graph Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50_graph_problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50_graph_problems/</guid><description>Top 50 Graph Problems Looking to master graph theory and solve graph problems efficiently? You&amp;rsquo;re in the right place! This blog provides solutions to the top 50 graph problems along with multiple approaches for each problem. We also ensure that the written code is well-commented for better understanding.
Graphs are essential data structures used in various fields, including computer science, data analysis, and network analysis. By gaining proficiency in graph theory and problem-solving, you can enhance your skills and tackle complex challenges effectively.</description></item><item><title>Top 50 Tree Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-tree-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-tree-problems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Database Sharding</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-sharding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-sharding/</guid><description>What is Database Sharding Sharding is a type of database partitioning that separates large databases into smaller, faster, more easily managed parts. These smaller parts are called data shards. The word shard means &amp;ldquo;a small part of a whole.&amp;rdquo;
Horizontal Vs vertical sharding: To achieve sharding, the rows or columns of a larger database table are split into multiple smaller tables.
When we split using rows : Horizontal Sharding
When we split using columns : Vertical Sharding</description></item><item><title>Top Github Commands that you should know</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/git-commands-that-you-should-know/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/git-commands-that-you-should-know/</guid><description>GitHub Commands Tutorial Table of Contents Configuring GitHub Creating a New Repository Cloning a Repository Adding Files to a Repository Committing Changes Pushing Changes to GitHub Pulling the Latest Version from GitHub Creating a New Branch Switching Between Branches Merging Branches Configuring GitHub Before using Git commands, make sure to configure your GitHub account. You need to set your email address and username with the following commands:
git config --global user.</description></item><item><title>Top 50 DP Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-dp-problems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-dp-problems/</guid><description>List Of Questions: Subset Sum Problem Longest Common Subsequence Longest Increasing Subsequence Edit Distance Longest Path In Matrix Optimal Strategy for a Game 0-1 Knapsack Problem Shortest Common Supersequence Partition problem Rod Cutting Coin change problem Word Break Problem Dice Throw Problem Box Stacking Egg Dropping Puzzle Max length chain Longest Common Substring Interleaved strings Maximum sum increasing subsequence Minimum number of jumps Count subsequences of type a^i, b^j, c^k Get Minimum Squares Nth Fibonacci Number Longest Palindromic Substring Total Decoding Messages Unique BST’s Player with max score Form a palindrome Word Wrap Problem Count Palindromic Subsequences Minimum time to finish tasks without skipping two consecutive Minimum Partition Boolean Parenthesization Problem Matrix Chain Multiplication Subset Sum Problem Given an array of non-negative integers, and a value sum, determine if there is a subset of the given set with sum equal to given sum.</description></item><item><title>Top 50 Graph Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-replication/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-replication/</guid><description>Understanding Database Replication in System Design Introduction Database replication is a technique used to maintain the same data across different databases. The primary goal is to ensure data reliability, redundancy, and availability. In system design, replication is crucial for preventing data loss, load balancing, and improving local data access speed. It is a fundamental concept often discussed during interviews related to system design.
Database Replication Types There are three main types of database replication:</description></item></channel></rss>