<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Vaibhav's Blogs</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Vaibhav's Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top 50 Graph Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50_graph_problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50_graph_problems/</guid><description>Top 50 Graph Problems Looking to master graph theory and solve graph problems efficiently? You&amp;rsquo;re in the right place! This blog provides solutions to the top 50 graph problems along with multiple approaches for each problem. We also ensure that the written code is well-commented for better understanding.
Graphs are essential data structures used in various fields, including computer science, data analysis, and network analysis. By gaining proficiency in graph theory and problem-solving, you can enhance your skills and tackle complex challenges effectively.</description></item><item><title>Top 50 Tree Questions</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-tree-problems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/top-50-tree-problems/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Database Sharding</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-sharding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:10:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/database-sharding/</guid><description>What is Database Sharding Sharding is a type of database partitioning that separates large databases into smaller, faster, more easily managed parts. These smaller parts are called data shards. The word shard means &amp;ldquo;a small part of a whole.&amp;rdquo;
Horizontal Vs vertical sharding: To achieve sharding, the rows or columns of a larger database table are split into multiple smaller tables.
When we split using rows : Horizontal Sharding
When we split using columns : Vertical Sharding</description></item><item><title>Top Github Commands that you should know</title><link>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/git-commands-that-you-should-know/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 15:10:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://Vaibhav-sarvashreshth.github.io/blog/posts/git-commands-that-you-should-know/</guid><description>GitHub Commands Tutorial Table of Contents Configuring GitHub Creating a New Repository Cloning a Repository Adding Files to a Repository Committing Changes Pushing Changes to GitHub Pulling the Latest Version from GitHub Creating a New Branch Switching Between Branches Merging Branches Configuring GitHub Before using Git commands, make sure to configure your GitHub account. You need to set your email address and username with the following commands:
git config --global user.</description></item></channel></rss>